<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://hwameistor.io/blog</id>
    <title>HwameiStor Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://hwameistor.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>HwameiStor Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://hwameistor.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LV and LVReplica]]></title>
        <id>3</id>
        <link href="https://hwameistor.io/blog/3"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Kubernetes, when a PVC is created and uses HwameiStor as its local storage, HwameiStor will create two kinds of CR: LocalVolume and LocalVolumeReplica. Why create these two resources for one PV? Continue to read and you will find the answer.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Kubernetes, when a PVC is created and uses HwameiStor as its local storage, HwameiStor will create two kinds of CR: <code>LocalVolume</code> and <code>LocalVolumeReplica</code>. Why create these two resources for one PV? Continue to read and you will find the answer.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LV Replicas" src="/assets/images/lv_replicas_en-b8df5dbb116d4022b977b52e573d7bc2.png" width="1838" height="1146" class="img_E7b_"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="localvolume">LocalVolume<a class="hash-link" href="#localvolume" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><code>LocalVolume</code> is a CRD defined by HwameiStor. It is the volume that HwameiStor provides for users. Each <code>LocalVolume</code> corresponds to a <code>PersistentVolume</code> of Kubernetes. Both are volumes, but <code>LocalVolume</code> stores HwameiStor-related information, while the other records information about Kubernetes itself and links it to <code>LocalVolume</code>.</p><p>You can check details of <code>LocalVolume</code> with this command:</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_I0IT theme-code-block"><div class="codeBlockContent_wNvx" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_jd64 thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_mRuA"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">#  check status of local volume and volume replica</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$ kubectl get lv # or localvolume</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">NAME                                       POOL                   KIND   REPLICAS   CAPACITY     ACCESSIBILITY   STATE      RESOURCE   PUBLISHED   AGE</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">pvc-996b05e8-80f2-4240-ace4-5f5f250310e2   LocalStorage_PoolHDD   LVM    1          1073741824   k8s-node1       Ready   -1                     22m</span><br></span></code></pre><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="copyButton_eDfN clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_W9eQ" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_XEyF" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_i9w9" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div><p>Now that HwameiStor can use <code>LocalVolume</code> to provide a volume, why do we still need <code>LocalVolumeReplica</code>?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="localvolumereplica">LocalVolumeReplica<a class="hash-link" href="#localvolumereplica" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><code>LocalVolumeReplica</code> is another CRD defined by HwameiStor. It represents a replica of a volume.</p><p>In HwameiStor, <code>LocalVolume</code> can specify one of its <code>LocalVolumeReplica</code> as the active replica. As a volume, <code>LocalVolume</code> can have many <code>LocalVolumeReplica</code> as its replicas. The replica in active state will be mounted by applications and others will stand by as high available replicas.</p><p>You can check details of <code>LocalVolumeReplica</code> with this command:</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_I0IT theme-code-block"><div class="codeBlockContent_wNvx" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_jd64 thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_mRuA"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$ kubectl get lvr # or localvolumereplica</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">NAME                                              KIND   CAPACITY     NODE        STATE   SYNCED   DEVICE                                                               AGE</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">pvc-996b05e8-80f2-4240-ace4-5f5f250310e2-v5scm9   LVM    1073741824   k8s-node1   Ready   true     /dev/LocalStorage_PoolHDD/pvc-996b05e8-80f2-4240-ace4-5f5f250310e2   80s</span><br></span></code></pre><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="copyButton_eDfN clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_W9eQ" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_XEyF" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_i9w9" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div><p><code>LocalVolumeReplica</code> allows HwameiStor to support features like HA, migration, hot standby of volumes and fast recovery of Kubernetes applications, making it more competitive as a local storage tool.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a class="hash-link" href="#conclusion" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p><code>LocalVolume</code> and <code>LocalVolumeReplica</code> are common concepts in many storage products, but each product can have its own competitive and unique features based on these two concepts. A technical difficulty can be solved with different solutions, so these concepts are also suitable for different production scenarios.</p><p>We will provide more capabilities for more scenarios in future releases. Both users and developers are welcome to join us!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Lechuan Niu</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/niulechuan</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
        <category label="Hwameistor" term="Hwameistor"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reliable Helper System for HwameiStor Is Online]]></title>
        <id>2</id>
        <link href="https://hwameistor.io/blog/2"/>
        <updated>2022-05-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[News today: The HwameiStor Reliable Helper System, an automatic and reliable cloud-native local storage maintenance system dedicated to system operation and maintenance, has been launched.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>News today: The HwameiStor Reliable Helper System, an automatic and reliable cloud-native local storage maintenance system dedicated to system operation and maintenance, has been launched.</p></blockquote><p>DaoCloud officially opens source of HwameiStor Reliable Helper System, a cloud native, automatic, reliable local storage maintenance system. This system is still in the alpha stage. HwameiStor creates a local storage pool with HDD, SSD, and NVMe disks for a central management. As the underlying data base used by applications, disks often face risks such as natural and unintentional damage. In this case, the Reliable Helper System comes out for disk operation and maintenance. All developers and enthusiasts are welcome to try it out.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="System architecture" src="/assets/images/HwameiStor-replace-disk-arch-c66fff2c76854dc33971e990f2b1b061.jpg" width="792" height="731" class="img_E7b_"></p><p>In the cloud native era, application developers can focus on the business logic itself, while the agility, scalability, and reliability required by the application runtime attribute to the infrastructure platform and O\&amp;M team. The HwameiStor Reliable Helper System is a reliable operation and maintenance system that meets the requirements of the cloud-native era. Currently, it supports the feature of one-click disk replacement.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="comprehensively-enhance-the-operation-and-maintenance">Comprehensively enhance the operation and maintenance<a class="hash-link" href="#comprehensively-enhance-the-operation-and-maintenance" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="reliable-one-click-replacement-alert-reminder">Reliable, one-click replacement, alert reminder<a class="hash-link" href="#reliable-one-click-replacement-alert-reminder" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><p>Reliable data migration and backfill</p><p>Automatically recognize RAID disks and determine if the data migration and backfill is required to guarantee data reliability.</p></li><li><p>One-click disk replacement</p><p>This feature is implemented by using the disk uuid.</p></li><li><p>Intuitive alert reminder</p><p>If any exceptions occur in the process of one-click disk replacement, the system will raise an alert to remind you.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="join-us">Join us<a class="hash-link" href="#join-us" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>If the coming future is an era of intelligent Internet, developers will be the pioneers to that milestone, and the open source community will become the "metaverse" of developers.</p><p>If you have any questions about the HwameiStor cloud-native local storage system, welcome to join the community to explore this metaverse world dedicated for developers and grow together.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jie Li</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/angel0507</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
        <category label="Hwameistor" term="Hwameistor"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HwameiStor Comes Online]]></title>
        <id>1</id>
        <link href="https://hwameistor.io/blog/1"/>
        <updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HwameiStor, an automated, highly available, cloud native, local storage system, is coming online]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>HwameiStor, an automated, highly available, cloud native, local storage system, is coming online</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="HwameiStor" src="/assets/images/HwameiStor-b1534b2445747773ba035b59d9a2e4d9.png" width="900" height="383" class="img_E7b_"></p><blockquote><p>News today: The local storage system provided by HwameiStor is creating a new land of "metaverse" that belongs to developers and evolves rapidly, waiting for you to join.</p></blockquote><p>Daocloud officially launched the open source project today. HwameiStor creates a local storage resource pool for centrally managing all disks such as HDD, SSD, and NVMe. It uses the CSI architecture to provide distributed services with local volumes, and provides data persistence capabilities for stateful cloud-native workloads or components.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="System architecture" src="/assets/images/architect-5b800d6ed2893aea97ee9b52dd53a1a2.jpg" width="1080" height="423" class="img_E7b_"></p><p>In the cloud native era, application developers can focus on the business logic itself, while the agility, scalability, and reliability required by the application runtime attribute to the infrastructure platform and O&amp;M team. <strong>Hwameistor is a storage system that grows in the cloud native era. </strong>It has the advantages of high availability, automation, cost-efficiency, rapid deployment, and high performance. It can replace the expensive traditional SAN storage.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="the-local-storage-is-smart-stable-and-agile">The local storage is smart, stable, and agile<a class="hash-link" href="#the-local-storage-is-smart-stable-and-agile" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><p>Automatic operation and maintenance management</p><p>Automatically discover, identify, manage, and allocate disks. Intelligently schedule applications and data based on affinity. Automatically monitor the disk status and give early warning in time.</p></li><li><p>Highly available data</p><p>Use inter-node replicas to synchronize data for high availability. When a problem occurs, the application will be automatically scheduled to a highly available data node to guarantee the application continuity.</p></li><li><p>Multiple data volume types are supported</p><p>Aggregate HDD, SSD, and NVMe disks to provide data service with low latency and high throughput.</p></li><li><p>Flexible and dynamic linear expansion</p><p>A dynamic expansion is supported according to the cluster size, to flexibly meet the data persistence needs of applications.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="enrich-scenarios-and-widely-adapt-to-enterprise-needs">Enrich scenarios and widely adapt to enterprise needs<a class="hash-link" href="#enrich-scenarios-and-widely-adapt-to-enterprise-needs" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><p>Adapt to middlewares with high available architecture</p><p>Kafka, Elasticsearch, Redis, and other middleware applications have high available architecture and strict requirements for IO data access. The LVM-based single-replica local data volume provided by HwameiStor can well meet their requirements.</p></li><li><p>Provide highly available data volumes for applications</p><p>MySQL and other OLTP databases require the underlying storage to provide highly available data storage, which can quickly restore data in case of problems. At the same time, it is also required to guarantee high-performance data access. The dual-replica high available data volume provided by HwameiStor can well meet such requirements.</p></li><li><p>Automated operation and maintenance of traditional storage software</p><p>MinIO, Ceph, and other storage software need to use the disks on a kubernetes node. These software can utilize PVC/PV to automatically use the single-replica local volume of HwameiStor through CSI drivers, quickly respond to the deployment, expansion, migration, and other requests from the business system, and realize the automatic operation and maintenance based on Kubernetes.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="join-us">Join us<a class="hash-link" href="#join-us" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>If the coming future is an era of intelligent Internet, developers will be the pioneers to that milestone, and the open source community will become the "metaverse" of developers.</p><p>If you have any questions about the HwameiStor cloud-native local storage system, welcome to join the community to explore this metaverse world dedicated for developers and grow together.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Yao</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/windsonsea</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
        <category label="Hwameistor" term="Hwameistor"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>welcome</id>
        <link href="https://hwameistor.io/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the Hwameistor blog space.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the Hwameistor blog space.</p><p>Here you can keep up with the progress of the Hwameistor open source project and recent hot topics.</p><p>We also plan to include release notes for major releases, guidance articles, community-related events, and possibly some development tips, and interesting topics within the team.</p><p>If you are interested in contributing to this open source project and would like to join the discussion or make some guest blog posts, please contact us.</p><p>GitHub address is: <a href="https://github.com/hwameistor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/hwameistor</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Yao</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/windsonsea</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
        <category label="Hwameistor" term="Hwameistor"/>
    </entry>
</feed>